Inventory of the Harrison Holt Riddleberger Papers 1874-1902
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Harrison Holt Riddleberger Addition
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 January 18. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Senate letterhead. He is going to speak on Monday (court day), giving a "send off" to a new scheme.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Virginia Hotel, to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 January 26. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Has been working on his speech and is almost "too nervous to write." Invites her up to D.C. because he cannot come home.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 January 27. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Senate letterhead. Sends $20 to supply "your wants." Also sends check for $28, and asks for $15 to be sent to Dr. Campbell.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 February 5. (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 February 9. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Senate letterhead. Working on the Debt bill. Will attend the meeting on the new Revenue bill.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 February 14. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Senate letterhead.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 February 18. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Working on the debt bill and claims that they are "filibustering all around." Encloses $20.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 February 21. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Senate letterhead. Writes letter while the senators are talking about a railroad bill.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 February 27. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Senate letterhead. Explains that money is being used to defeat the debt bill.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 March 2. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Senate letterhead. (Debt?) Bill is passed, creating great excitement. Anticipates a veto.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Petersburg, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 August. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Reports that he is giving speeches in Suffolk and Portsmouth to audiences of 1500-3000. Claims that the trip is a tremendous strain and great success.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Petersburg, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 August 5. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Reports that he is giving speeches in Suffolk, Norfolk and Portsmouth.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1880 September 8. (Box-folder 4:2)
    "Whig" Building letterhead. Has returned from the "third discussion of the week." Makes reference to telegram in Whig. Visited with Gen. M. [General Mahone].
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. [1881]. (Box-folder 4:3)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Enclosed check for $175.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. [1881]. (Box-folder 4:3)
    Delegates have arrived from Virginia for a committee meeting.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Petersburg, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. [1881] (Box-folder 4:3)
    Gen. M. [General Mahone] is compelled to postpone his appointment. Will return home Friday and Saturday. Will meet some friends in Norfolk.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 January 9. (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 January 13. (Box-folder 4:3)
    Has received letters about a small pox threat. Hopes that his wife and children will be vaccinated. He was vaccinated on Sunday night, because there have been 100 cases in the city.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 March 22. (Box-folder 4:3)
    He is sending ribbons for his daughters and is preparing to go home.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 March 24. (Box-folder 4:3)
    He has been nominated for the position of Sargent at Arms and there has been debate about this position. Debate directed against the debt bill.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 April 3. (Box-folder 4:3)
    U.S. Senate Chamber letterhead. Debates in the Senate continue.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 April 7. (Box-folder 4:3)
    U.S. Senate Chamber letterhead. Senate has adjourned and he believes that the controversy will end soon. Claims that he is preparing his indictment for the grand jury and the "men now in jail."
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 April 12. (Box-folder 4:3)
    "The Arlington" letterhead. Has been offered $200 to lecture for 25 nights.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 April 21. (Box-folder 4:3)
    U.S. Senate Chamber letterhead. Tensions in the senate continue. Mentions the possibility of being elected in December.
  - Harrison Holt Riddlberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 April 28. (Box-folder 4:3)
    U.S. Senate Chamber letterhead. Doing work for Gen. M. [General Mahone] relating to the convention of June 2nd.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 July 27. (Box-folder 4:3)
    " The Whig" letterhead. Written onboard the C & O train.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Norforlk, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 August 1. (Box-folder 4:3)
    "Purcell House" letterhead. Returned from visit to Pt. Anne with personal and political friends. Will depart (by rail) to see "Ocean View" with friends.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Petersburg, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 August 8. (Box-folder 4:3)
    Has returned from Sussex, having completed his travels by rail. Asks her to "clip and preserve" all of the material published about his speeches.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Petersburg, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 August 9. (Box-folder 4:3)
    Gen. M. [General Mahone] is trying to postpone the Fairfax barbeque and is very anxious that Riddleberger attend. Thursday morning he will speak for his friend Wilcox.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Petersburg, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 September 2. (Box-folder 4:3)
    Will speak that evening in the Academy of Music and anticipates an immense audience.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Petersburg, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 September 3. (Box-folder 4:3)
    Asks her to send any mail to the Whig office this week.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 December 8. (Box-folder 4:3)
    Senate Chamber letterhead. Senate contest is "very warm" and claims that all "batteries" seem directed against him.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 December 14. (Box-folder 4:3)
    Senate Chamber letterhead. Received a unanimous nomination.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Richmond, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1881 December 15. (Box-folder 4:3)
    Senate Chamber letterhead.
  - (Box-folder 4:)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1882 January 27. (Box-folder 4:4)
    Will go to Washington to spend Sunday with Gen. M. [General Mahone].
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1882 February 1. (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to his children. 1882 February 28. (Box-folder 4:4)
    Senate Chamber letterhead. Wife will stay with him until Saturday.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1882 March 20. (Box-folder 4:4)
    Senate Chamber letterhead. Sick from eating roasted oysters.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1882 March 23. (Box-folder 4:4)
    Senate Chamber letterhead. Encloses check for $150, with detailed list of whom to send the money to.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1882 April 4. (Box-folder 4:4)
    Senate Chamber letterhead. All voted down a resolution to adjourn Saturday. Excitement in the Senate over three "readjusters who have gone away from us." Opposition to the "farmers law."
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1882 April 10. (Box-folder 4:4)
    Trying to sell his horse.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1882 April 12. (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1882 April 18. (Box-folder 4:4)
    Unexpectedly called to Washington. Must take charge of a new tax bill, because he is chairman of finance. Will have a conference to determine how long they will remain in Richmond.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1883 November 28. (Box-folder 4:5)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Visited with Frank and [Lallie?]. Has new quarters with excellent furnishings. Spent the day with Gen. M. [General Mahone] Preparations are being made for Thanksgiving. Mrs. M. is coming to visit. Will make calls to some of the older senators with Gen. M. [General Mahone].
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1883 December 9. (Box-folder 4:5)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Will vote on organization on December 10th. Gen. M. and family are at the Arlington and he is encouraging Riddleberger to "move up there," but Riddleberger has declined.
  - (Box-folder 4:)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. [1884]. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Written on a Sunday in 1884. Sends $10 for a birthday, $10 for debts. Went to see a play at the National. Gets sick and is treated by Dr. [Strayer?].
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 January 7. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Letter written while in session, from his desk. Visits with Frank and [Lallie?].
  - (Box-folder 4:)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 January 21. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Suddenly called to N.Y. Encloses $50, with $30 for Mr. Geary.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 January 30. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Family has measles. Mentions working through the Mississippi resolution, more quickly than expected, because the opposition changed their policy.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 February 8. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Mentions sending valentines to children [Lilia, Olive, and Ned?]
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 February 18. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Plans to stay in NY a day longer to see "Big City." Visits St. James Hotel. Has sent valentines to family.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 March 3. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 March 13. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 March 20. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 April 3. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 April 10. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 April 14. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 April 18. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Writes letter while in executive session. Has called twice to see Mrs. A., but was unsuccessful. Asks his wife to tell Hugh that he "gave her the knife."
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 April 22. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 May 4. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Guest of the Potomac Boat Club.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 June 16. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Describes stomach ailment.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 June 24. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 July 2. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Sends groceries this morning. He is feeling better-recovering from an attack of dysentery that lasted for 4 days.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his son. 1884 December 7. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Writes about his hopes for his son's future.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1884 December 12. (Box-folder 4:6)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Writes to tell his wife that he is assisting her father financially, but requests that she not disclose this to anyone.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1885 January 9. (Box-folder 4:7)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Discusses dentistry in the city vs. country.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1885 January 11. (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his children. 1885 January 11. (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his son. 1886 February 25. (Box-folder 4:8)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Sends son badge given to him at Newark. Encourages his son to study Revolutionary war period.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1886 February 28. (Box-folder 4:8)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Only Virginian to support "Educational Bill." Expresses his dedication to the impoverished. Encourages Mrs. Riddleberger to come visit him.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington, D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1886 April 23. (Box-folder 4:8)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Claims that the upcoming horse races will be the "best ever known in this country." Writes about family garden. Mentions adjustment of Hawkin's claim. Encourages his wife to send others to the horse races as visitors.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1886 May 1. (Box-folder 4:8)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Gave speech at the Irish meeting, which will appear in the papers. Attempts to explain to his wife why he cannot come home. Tells her that he is chairman of a subcommittee "taking evidence on an executive appointment, pending in Executive session." Taking quinine for illness, although feeling better.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1886 May 5. (Box-folder 4:8)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Sends check for $30 to meet wife's home obligations and to buy tickets. Had flower bulbs shipped to her.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1886 May 22. (Box-folder 4:8)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Writes to her while a debate is going on. Claims that Gen M. [General Mahone] has not been "in his seat an average of half hour a day" and Virginia matters are piled up as a result. Wishes that he could be at the commencement.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1886 June 22. (Box-folder 4:8)
    Return trip from Mt. Vernon. Horse develops illness. Tells wife that he will inform her if he successfully sells the horse, when it is well enough to be exhibited.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. U.S. 1886 June 24. (Box-folder 4:8)
    Senate letterhead. Said to be the most "unhealthy June known here in years, the city is filled with sick."
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington D.C. to his Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1887 April 5. (Box-folder 4:9)
    E.E. White letterhead. "Broken promises" have kept him in DC for longer than intended. Wants the Herald issued before he returns home. Got a cold from "tramping through a Washington snow storm," but is in better health.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. 1887 December 16. (Box-folder 4:9)
    E.E. White letterhead. Has sent wife "three short cloaks (?)". Plans to go home in the following week.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington D.C. to his wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. n.d. (Box-folder 4:10)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Written on a Thursday, in the Committee Room of the District of Columbia. Bad weather and icy streets has lead to at least 2 deaths "from falling."
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. n.d. (Box-folder 4:10)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Sends $30 and explains how the money should be spent, which includes getting a "quarter of beef" and a "barrel of flour." Plans to go to New York the following week.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. U.S. Senate letterhead. Written on a Saturday night. Senate has adjourned until Monday. n.d. (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Richmond, Va. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. n.d. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Written on a Monday night. Expresses homesickness. Refers to Hunter's article, a man who he claims has a "special spite" for him.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington, D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. n.d. (Box-folder 4:10)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Written on Thursday at 6 pm.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Washington, D.C. to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. n.d. (Box-folder 4:10)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Children have the measles and inquires whether it is safe for him to return home.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger. Petersburg, VA to wife Emma Belew Riddleberger. n.d. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Written on back of Re-Adjustment in Other Southern States. Has spent the day with Gen M [General Mahone].
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger and child(ren) to Emma Belew Riddleberger. Sends birthday congratulations. n.d. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Tells Mrs. Riddleberger that her birthday gift will be a piano cover.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Surry, Va. to Emma Belew Riddleberger. n.d. (Box-folder 4:10)
    Working on adjustment and trying to find a time to go home via train.
  - Harrison Holt Riddleberger, Washington, D.C. to Emma Belew Riddleberger. n.d. (Box-folder 4:10)
    U.S. Senate letterhead. Mentions box of flowers for Ned's birthday.
  - Envelope to Ms. Emma Riddleberger. 4 December 1884. (Box-folder 4:10)